It should be noted that anything we build can be moved and fliped w/o consequences as long as it done in unison to the rest of the beings.
define: 
Point (a place with no size) [p]
Line (a place with one size, length)
unit length, (a line to which any other will be compared in size).
	 the length of a line a will be defined by the ratio (a/unit length)
	points can be placed anywhere on a line. in particular a line have specific points in its ends and can so be defined [I(pa, pb)]
lines can be devided infinatly to smaller lines
in particular when two lines meet at a single point which is not the end of either of them we can regard the parts of the first line from one side and the other side of the second line as two lines and the two parts of the second line in kind
line are flipable hence any line with a given length is similar to any else with this length,
but when we have more than a single line they are to be fliped togheter hence they keep a differance in slope, this diference will be defiend in time.

circle (the place defined by a point called a center [o] and a length) 
	the circle include all the points that can define a line of that length together with this o) 
	all lines thus difined ara called a radius [R] of this circle
	so the circle can be notated [C(O,R)]
the length of every circle has the same ratio to its radius, aproximatly 6.283185307179586476925286766559. this number is notated 2π, 
hence the length of every part of a circle can be defined by any rational multiplyers of π between 2 and 0

now let us take 2 lines that meet at one of their ends
and let us regard that end a center of a circle,
the two lines togheter divied this circle to two parts, "internal" and "external" 
we can define the difference in slope between the lines by the length of this two parts, for convenience sake we regard always the internal.
this length divided by the radius of the circle will defined the difference in slope and will be called the angle of this lines.
when two lines meet in their middles, the angle between the first parts of either and the other part of either will at any circumstance be equal
we call lines whice the angle between any part of the one and part of the second is π/2 perpenticular or perp in short. all four angle must be equal to that value becouse π/2 is the 1/4 of 2π.

let us draw two perpendicular lines that will be as long as we will need. we will call the one the x axis and the other the y axis, and let us call the point of their meeting the origin (0,0) we call them Cartesian coordinate system
we can define any point in relation to the origin thus, let us draw from the point a line perpendicular to the x axis and call it m, and we will call the legnth of m the y value of the point, and we will call the length between the origin and the meeting point of the x axis and m the x value of the point
hence the point will be defined by this two values (x value, y value)
in the same manner we could have used a line perpendicular to the y axis.


(we will find that for lines who meet in more than one point, both the internal and the external angle are π and they togheter form a line
this is becouse a line halves a circle if it cross the circle's centre) 
